

eduardocsilva2000@gmail.com

+351 910597715

Porto, Portugal

eduardocsilva.github.io

github.com/eduardocsilva

SOFT SKILLS

Communication

Leadership

Teamwork

Flexibility

Proactivity

Independence

**Problem Solving** 

## **LANGUAGES**

Portuguese

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Enalish

Full Professional Proficiency

## **INTERESTS**

Programming

Technology

Artificial Intelligence

Web Development

Reading

Music

Sports

# Eduardo Silva

Informatics Engineering Student

An independent and self-motivated student pursuing a Bachelor's Degree in Informatics Engineering at Instituto Superior de Engenharia do Porto (current average grade: 17,8 / 20), with a strong background in Software Engineering and Web Development, as well as Data Structures and Algorithms. Strong team spirit and creativity due to the 9 years as a federated football player and 4 years of experience as a musician.

## **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor's Degree in Informatics Engineering** Instituto Superior de Engenharia do Porto

Current Average Grade: 17,8 / 20

Final Average Grade: 19 / 20

- Software and Application Engineering
  - Systems Arquitecture and Administration
- Advanced Algorithms and Data Structures
- Linear Algebra and Computational Mathematics

Sciences and Technologies - High School

Escola Secundária de Valongo

09/2015 - 07/2018

# WORK EXPERIENCE

**Member of Informatics Department** Núcleo de Estudantes de Informática - ISEP

03/2021 - Present Porto

**Drum Teacher** Academia Dó Ré Mi

09/2019 - Present Valongo, Porto

# **PROJECTS**

Laboratory and Project 5 - Public Transport Planning and Management App (09/2020 - Present) Technologies Used: Node.js, React/Redux, C#, .NET Core, SQL Server, MongoDB, UML, etc. (Grade: 19 / 20)

Laboratory and Project 4 - Factory Floor Management Application (03/2020 - 07/2020) Technologies Used: Java, C, JSON, XML, XSD, XSL, H2 SQL, UML (Grade: 19 / 20)

Laboratory and Project 3 - Ride-Sharing Management Application (09/2019 - 01/2020) Technologies Used: Java, JPA, Oracle SQL, UML (Grade: 19 / 20)

Laboratory and Project 2 - Domestic Services Management Application (03/2019 - 07/2019) Technologies Used: Java, JavaFX, UML (Grade: 17 / 20)

Laboratory and Project 1 - Social Network Analysis Application (09/2018 - 01/2019) Technologies Used: Java (Grade: 16 / 20)

### CERTIFICATES

Machine Learning - Stanford University (Coursera) (08/2020 - 11/2020)

Introduction to Machine Learning (Supervised and Unsupervised Learning), Data Mining and Statistical Pattern Recognition

## HARD SKILLS

Languages: Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript/TypeScript, Java, C#, C, C++, Prolog

Frameworks & Libraries: Scikit-Learn, Tensorflow, FastAPI, Express.js, .NET Core, React, Redux

Databases: MongoDB, MySQL, MariaDB, SQL Server, Oracle SQL, H2

Testing: Unit, Integration, Smoke, API, End 2 End

#### OTHER SKILLS

Musician (10/2017 - Present)

Guitarist for 3 years, Ballroom Dancer for 2 years and Drummer for 1.5 years

Federated Football Player (08/2008 - 08/2017)

Goalkeeper for the clubs União Desportiva Valonguense (2008-2014) and União Desportiva Sousense (2014-2017)